bzzagent.com 2018-06-16

# BzzAgent Privacy Notice | the short version...

Last updated: May, 2018

#### 1\. Introduction

1.1 dunnhumby respects your right to privacy. This Privacy Notice explains who we are, how we collect, share and use information about you (including information about you from which you can be directly or indirectly identified in particular by reference to an identifier), and how you can exercise your privacy rights when you register as a member of the BzzAgent community. For information about how we handle other (i.e., non-personal) information, please see the BzzAgent terms and conditions.

1.2 This Privacy Notice applies to information that we collect via the website at [http://www.bzzagent.co.uk](http://www.bzzagent.co.uk/) and [http://www.bzzagent.com](http://www.bzzagent.com/).

1.3 If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your information, then please contact us using the contact details provided at the bottom of this Privacy Notice.

#### 2\. Quick Links

2.1 We recommend that you read this Privacy Notice in full to ensure you are fully informed. However, if you only want to access a particular section of this Privacy Notice, then you can click on the relevant link below to jump to that section.

#### 3\. What does dunnhumby do?

3.1 dunnhumby is a consumer data science company, headquartered in the U.K. but with group companies all around the world. Our products and services help retailers and brands analyse data in order to improve consumer experiences and build loyalty. 

3.2 For more information about dunnhumby, please see the “About Us” section of our website at <https://www.dunnhumby.com/about-us>.

#### 4\. What is BzzAgent?

BzzAgent is a community of everyday influencers, real everyday people who enjoy sharing their experiences with brands and products. BzzAgents participate in campaigns where they try products and share their authentic and honest opinions. This can be in the form of creating and sharing a photo or post with friends and followers via social media platforms including Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, SnapChat, and blogs. It can also be in the form of submitting product reviews which may be shared to brand and ecommerce sites. Through these social posts and reviews, users help drive brand awareness and inform purchase decisions.

#### 5\. What information do we collect and why?

5.1 If you are a member of the BzzAgent community, we may collect the following information about you:

__Information that you provide voluntarily as a member of BzzAgent__

5.2 The types of information include the following:

(a) Contact details – name, street address, email address, username, home telephone number, mobile telephone number; 

(b) Demographic details – age, gender, date of birth, household income and family composition (i.e. number, age (birth month and year) and gender of children, we may also ask if the user is expecting or trying to conceive., if any);

(c) Survey details – results of online surveys relating to issues such as personality, values, attitudes, interests, and health and lifestyle (e.g. your diet and exercise preferences); 

(d) Psychographic details – results of questions as to whether you agree or disagree with certain value statements or behaviours (e.g. a healthy diet is part of my life); and

(e) If you provide consent, we will also pass along email, city, state and phone number to our client in the event that a member reports an adverse event for pharmacovigilance.

5.3 Occasionally, we will offer campaigns that relate to potentially sensitive topics such as health, wellness or sexual preference. As with all of our surveys, we are only asking the questions in order to best match you with the right campaigns.

5.4 In some countries we may also ask you to indicate your ethnicity or language on a purely voluntary basis. In Brazil we will ask users to sign up with a valid CPF number. Please do not provide this information if we do not ask for it.

__Information that we collect automatically__

5.5 When you use our website we will collect information about the types of campaigns you have opted-in to and the activities that you perform in those campaigns.

5.6 We may also collect certain information automatically from your device. In some countries, including countries in the European Economic Area, this information may be regulated under applicable data protection and privacy laws.

5.7 Specifically, the information we collect automatically may include your IP address, device type, unique device identification numbers, browser-type, broad geographic location (e.g. country or city-level location), mobile device category and operating system and other technical information. In addition, we collect information about how your device has interacted with our tool, including the pages accessed and links clicked as well as details of how you arrived at our website.

5.8 Some of this information may be collected using cookies and similar tracking technology. 

5.9 For further information about the types of cookies we use, why, and how you can control cookies, please see our Cookie Notice.

__Information that we collect automatically__

5.10 As part of being able to provide you with a direct link to Facebook, Instagram and Twitter (and any other social networking applications we may add) via the BzzAgent site, we will also be collecting personal information when you connect to these social networking applications via our sites for the same purposes and duration set out in the section called “How we use your information” below. 

5.11 Remember, your privacy settings on social network applications may determine what information we can collect. If you have given us permission, the information we collect from your social media profile may include:

(a) your name;

(b) your user ID;

(c) your e-mail address;

(d) your gender;

(e) your birthday;

(f) your current city;

(g) your profile picture;

(h) your URL;

(i) your “likes”;

(j) any content you post via the social networking application; 

(k) user IDs of your friends who have also connected through BzzAgent's portal; and

(l) your follower / friend count as well as “likes” and comments that you will receive on their own posts.

Remember, your privacy settings on social network applications may determine what information we can collect. If you are at all concerned about your privacy in the context of any social network applications, please refer to the privacy policies applicable to those websites. 

__Information that we obtain from third party sources__

5.12 From time to time, we may receive personal information about you from third party sources including public databases and data aggregators. The third party sources who we may obtain your information from are: Walgreen Co. and Proctor & Gamble. Before obtaining this information we first check that these third parties either have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted to disclose your personal information to us. Examples of the kinds of information that we obtain from third parties include:

(a) name;

(b) street address;

(c) age;

(d) your shopping habits;

(e) online user activity such as your posts on social networking sites;

(f) preferences and information about your lifestyle such as your hobbies and interests; and

(g) publicly available information such as user-generated content, blogs and postings.

#### 6\. How we use your information and the legal basis for processing it

6.1 We use the information you provide to us voluntarily to:

(a) register you as a BzzAgent member;

(b) select you for BzzAgent campaigns that you are most likely to enjoy and to notify you about new BzzAgent campaigns and specific BzzAgent campaign directives;

(c) share reviews that you will create with our client's syndication partner that, in turn, will be dispersed to varying sites;

(d) send you products or samples as part of a BzzAgent campaign;

(e) analyse the effectiveness of BzzAgent campaigns;

(f) Show our clients the content you create through campaigns and give them access to this content so they reuse it in their paid or owned media

(g) improve and evaluate our sites, your experience as a member, and our offerings to our clients;

(h) respond to your queries or comments;

(i) better understand what products or services may be of interest to you;

(j) help our clients and partners provide you with products, services and advertisements that are more likely to be suited to you (this is mandatory for some of our clients including Proctor & Gamble);

(k) contact you regarding products and services which may be of interest to you, including through promotional e-mails and social media messages such as Facebook Messenger or Instagram messages ; and

(l) carry out prize draws or competitions that you have entered.

We process the information you provide to us voluntarily for these purposes in order to enable you to use BzzAgent and for the benefit of BzzAgent and our clients. We will voluntarily ask for your consent prior to requesting any information about sensitive topics.

6.2 We collect information automatically about you to technically provide BzzAgent to you, and better understand how you use it, where you come from, and the parts of BzzAgent that are of interest to you. We use this information for our internal analytics purposes and to improve the quality and relevance of our tool to you. We use cookie tracking for the same purpose.

6.3 We use the information we collect from social networks to gather campaign analytics to measure the effectiveness of campaigns i.e. reach and engagement. We will use user generated content that was actively uploaded to our website or was created on our website and posted on members social accounts on their behalf for: (i) marketing material for BzzAgent; (ii) Facebook Ads created by BzzAgent on the client's behalf which are posted and “live” throughout the campaign's duration ; (iii) marketing material the client will create; (iv) advertisements made by the client; (v) analysing product insights by the client; and (vi) analysing for reporting purposes by the client.

6.4 We use the information we receive from these third parties to maintain and improve the accuracy of the records we hold about you and improve your experience as a member of the BzzAgent community.

6.5 If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use information about you, please contact us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below.

#### 7\. Use of Plugins

7.1 Our website uses social plugins (“plugins”) from social networks such as Facebook, Twitter.com, Instagram and Pinterest. These plugins can be identified by social network logos or by the “Like” button. A list of current plugins can be found at the following addresses:

Facebook: <http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>

Twitter: <https://dev.twitter.com/web/overview>

Instagram: <https://www.instagram.com/developer/embedding/>

Pinterest: <https://developers.pinterest.com/tools/widget-builder/>

7.2 When you visit one of our web pages with plugins installed and click on a social network plugin labelled with the social network logo, your browser creates a direct connection to the social network server. By connecting the plugin, the social network receives the information that you have visited the corresponding page of our website with your IP address. If you click on the social network logo button while you are logged into your social media account you can link the content on our site with your social media profile.

7.3 As operator of the website we do not receive any information regarding the nature of the data sent to the social network or how it is used, however such information may be provided to you by the social network. More information can be found on the social networks' websites such as:

Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>

Twitter: <https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en>

Instagram: <https://www.instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/>

Pinterest: <https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy>

7.4 If you do not want social networks to collect data about you via our website, you must log out of your social media accounts prior to visiting our website and disconnect your social media accounts from your BzzAgent account page.

8.1 We may disclose your information: 

(a) to our group companies. For example, we have one global access management system which is provided from the US. We also have a number of global access management and support teams.

(b) to our clients so that they can provide you with products, services and advertisements that are more likely to be suited to you. Our clients may use the information they receive about you to serve you advertisements that are more relevant to you.

(c) to third party services providers who help us provide BzzAgent, for example by hosting it, enabling certain features or functionality including user tracking, or by providing ancillary services such as support and maintenance, security technology, or helpdesk support to our employees and clients. The main third party service providers that we use for BzzAgent are as follows:

  * Amazon Web Services is used for cloud object storage specifically storing photo content if you uploaded any to our site.
  * Amazon Elasticsearch is utilized to store data collected from our internal logging systems to support and maintain our site.
  * Brightcove Video Platform will store video content if any videos are uploaded to our site.
  * Google Analytics is used to understand the usage of the tools to help us improve the platform. Google Analytics will give each user a unique tracking ID and will process your browsing data and device information.
  * PowerReviews and Bazaarvoice are our syndication partners. If you provide a review and upload to our site, the review will be shared to either PowerReviews or Bazaarvoice which then will be syndicated across ecommerce sites.
  * FogBugz is used for our helpdesk support. It is used to triage and respond to any questions or comments that we may receive from our contact us form or via email.

(d) to any competent law enforcement body, regulatory, government agency, court or other third party where we believe disclosure is necessary (i) as a matter of applicable law or regulation, (ii) to exercise, establish or defend our legal rights, or (iii) to protect your vital interests or those of any other person;

(e) to a potential buyer (and its agents and advisers) in connection with any proposed purchase, merger or acquisition of any part of our business, provided that we inform the buyer it must use your information only for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Notice;

(f) to any other person with your consent to the disclosure.

(g) to third parties who will use it for the purposes of advertising, marketing and/or providing products and services to you and to other consumers.

(h) to our clients or fulfillment partners; when you participate in a campaign, we can share your personal information to allow them to deliver the product samples or other campaign collateral.

(i) to our client(s) to help them understand the impact of their campaigns and to give them access to activities you performed and content you created in the campaigns you've participated in for them to reuse in their paid or owned media channels.

#### 9\. How does dunnhumby keep my information secure?

9.1 We use appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect the information that we collect and process about you. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your information. Access to your personal information is restricted to prevent unauthorised access, modification or misuse and is only permitted among our employees on a need-to-know basis.

#### 10\. International data transfers

10.1 Our servers are located in the United States and our group companies and third party service providers and partners operate around the world. 

10.2 As a result, your information may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection and privacy laws that are different to the laws of your country and, in some cases, may not be as protective.

10.3 However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Notice. These include implementing the European Commission's Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of information between our group companies, which require all group companies to protect information they process from the EEA in accordance with European Union data protection and privacy law. 

10.4 Our Standard Contractual Clauses can be provided on request. We have implemented similar appropriate safeguards with our third party service providers and partners and further details can be provided upon request.

#### 11\. Data retention

11.1 We normally retain the information we collect from you until you cease your membership of the BzzAgent community. We will also redact your information if you have not logged into your account for two years.

11.2 We may however keep your information for longer if we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements). When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

#### 12\. Children

12.1 We do not knowingly collect personal information about children under 18 years of age without permission from their parent or legal guardian. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 18 and believe your child has disclosed information about themselves, please contact us.

#### 13\. Your data protection and privacy rights

13.1 You have the following rights:

(a) If you wish to access, correct, update or request deletion of your information, you can do so at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below. 

Please note that as a member of BzzAgent you are able to make changes at any time to keep your personal information up to date. The fastest way to change personal information is to log on and simply click on "Account", then click on "Profile" and then click on the Pencil icon to update personal information.

If you would like to request a copy of your data you can do so by going to: “Account” and clicking “Data and Privacy” and then selecting “Request a copy of your info”.

If for any reason, you no longer wish to be a member of BzzAgent and wish to close your account with us, then please let us know using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below, so that we can delete your account. You can also close your account by going into the “Account” tab and selecting “Close Your Account” in the “Data and Privacy” section.

(b) In addition, you can object to processing of your information, ask us to restrict processing of your information or request portability of your information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below.

(c) You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by changing your preferences on the "Settings" section of your account or by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing e-mails we send you. To opt-out of other forms of marketing, then please contact us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below.

We may still contact you even if you have opted out of receiving marketing communications for transactional purposes, such as customer service, product information, or service or reminder notices.

(d) Similarly, if we have collected and process your information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

(e) You have the right to complain to an information authority about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local authority. (Contact details for authorities in the European Economic Area, Switzerland and certain non-European countries (including the US and Canada) are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).) 

13.2 We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their rights in accordance with applicable laws.

#### 14\. Updates to this Privacy Notice

14.1 We may update this Privacy Notice from time to time in response to changing legal, technical or business developments. When we update our Privacy Notice, we will take appropriate measures to inform you, consistent with the significance of the changes we make. We will obtain your consent to any material Privacy Notice changes if and where this is required by applicable data protection and privacy laws. 

14.2 You can see when this Privacy Notice was last updated by checking the “last updated” date displayed at the top of this Privacy Notice. 

#### 15\. How to contact us

15.1 If you need general support about your BzzAgent account, you can send an email to [support@bzzagent.com](mailto:support@bzzagent.com).

15.2 If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your information, please contact our Data Protection Officer using the following details: [legal.queries@dunnhumby.com](mailto:legal.queries@dunnhumby.com). The data controller of your information is the local dunnhumby entity in the country in which you are based.

15.3 If you are from certain regions like Europe you also have the right to lodge any complaints or concerns with your local data protection authority (DPA). You can find a list of the European DPAs here: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.html>.
